<resources>
    <string name="footer">Written with Compose Multiplatform for %1$s!</string>
    <string name="see_on_github">Check it out on GitHub</string>
    <string name="bio">I am an Android developer and Engineering Manager at Stø (BankID BankAxept). I have been making mobile apps for %1$s years, and have been an engineer for %2$s. I like my cats, tv shows, single player story-driven games, and avoiding conversations about hobbies so people don't think I am boring. I dislike billionaires, inequality, and hateful people. I also dislike people who do not release the Epstein files.\n\nWhen I am not writing code, I spend a lot of my time figuring out how to make the workday as smooth as possible. I am a huge proponent of effective communication, and hate the overly formal and rigid structures that a lot of companies try to use in the workplace.</string>
    <string name="website">Website</string>
    <string name="personal_title">Personal info</string>
    <string name="personal_message">I can't have a personal website without showing off the things that matter most: my partner, Stella, and my cats, Storm, Lupin, Grey Thing, and Broomhilda.</string>
    <string name="personal_soapbox">Though this website is mostly a portfolio of things I have done, the state of the world compels me to also use it as a soapbox. Since I was a teenager I have had a very strong moral compass. I really value equality and kindness and empathy over anything. When I filled out my US Census form in college, I wrote in “human” as a race because I think that is where the world needs to be. We are all here sharing this planet together. Borders are imaginary, and the earth is such a small part of the universe as a whole.\n\nBut now more than ever we are being grouped and divided. It is like we haven’t learned anything at all and wars are still being waged over stories told by desert farmers thousands of years ago. And if it isn’t beliefs, it is ideologies, or skin color, or economic situations. Just anything to attack our neighbors; the ones we share a common history with. If you go back far enough in history, we all have a shared origin, so why are there so many arbitrary definitions of what makes us different from each other when, at the core, we are all the same?\n\nThe US is currently being run into the ground and divided by a group of hateful bigots led by a small, angry man. Respect is out the window, and he has been able to prey on the innate animal fear of something different from yourself, causing previously kind and caring people to turn into rude, racist, prejudiced, and entitled individuals. A cadre of pedophilic liars has created a cult to manipulate people into their own personal army of hate under the guise of politics. The utter dismantling of the trust of both the government and the foundations of science will not affect just America, because it is something that can spread like a disease if we let it.\n\nGetting into specifics would make this much too long, and I would have trouble keeping this updated since there are new atrocities every day. We need to use our voices to fight this. We need to use our voices to fight for our neighbors. We need to use our voices to fight for science, and for reason, and for kindness. We need to use our voices to unite! The enemy is not the person who lives across the street. The enemy is the idea that the person who lives across the street is your enemy. The enemy is the people who are spreading that idea. Those people — the ones who control 99% of the resources — are the ones we need to stand up against. There are so many more of us than there are of them, and if we could all speak together we could not be beaten.\n\nIf you read this, thank you, and please speak up somewhere. If you read this and you disagree, please do some real introspection to figure out why you feel this way, and realize that somebody else has told you to be angry. You do not have to be hateful, that is your own choice. Which side of history do you want to be on?</string>
    <string name="projects_title">Things I made</string>
    <string name="work_title">Things I have worked on</string>
    <string name="school_title">Things they taught me</string>
    <string name="school_name">Louisiana State University</string>
    <string name="school_location">Baton Rouge, Louisiana, USA</string>
    <string name="school_degree">Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering</string>
    <string name="school_years">August 2009 - May 2013</string>
    <string name="school_description">When I was starting college, I was very close to going in to chemical engineering, because I loved chemistry. But the advisor told me being color blind could cause problems, so I took my interest in electronics and computers and went into electrical engineering instead. I spend my college years taking classes like circuits, microprocessors, optical electronics, control systems, and microfluidic biochips. I also took two semesters of C++, which made me promise to never be a software developer. It wasn’t until years later that I learned I didn’t hate programming, I just hated C++.\n\nOutside of class I worked the electrical engineering department’s help desk and spent some time as a network infrastructure technical for the university. I also was active in the LSU chapter of IEEE, eventually serving as President of the chapter during my senior year.</string>
    <string name="project_1_title">PICKY</string>
    <string name="project_1_description">A collaborative effort between myself and tattoo artist Gunnar V, PICKY aims to help tattoo artists focus on their art by making all of the other stuff a lot easier.\n\nThe app handles things like client and ink management, helps pick which inks you should use to tattoo an image and helps mix inks to make other colors. It also has a handful of built-in algorithms to make stencils specifically for tattooing, letting you print these stencils directly from the app.</string>
    <string name="project_2_title">Home server</string>
    <string name="project_2_description">I also have a Linux server I tinker with. This helps me make sure I'm only mostly super specialized in app development. It has the added benefit of me being able to understand up to half of what the backend and dev ops people are talking about in meetings!\n\nI use Mint because I'm afraid of headless (go ahead, judge me) and manage all of my services with Docker. I manage a bunch of things for my household like a personal media server, home automation, and a private cloud. It is also a fun testing ground for me to try out other things like self hosted LLMs.</string>
</resources>