<resources>
    <string name="footer">Written with Compose Multiplatform for %1$s!</string>
    <string name="see_on_github">Check it out on GitHub</string>
    <string name="bio">I am an Android developer and Engineering Manager at Stø (BankID BankAxept). I have been making Android apps for %1$s years, and have been an engineer for %2$s. I like my cats, tv shows, single player story-driven games, and avoiding conversations about hobbies so people don't think I am boring. I dislike billionaires, inequality, and hateful people. I also dislike people who do not release the Epstein files.</string>
    <string name="personal_title">Personal info</string>
    <string name="personal_message">I can't have a personal website without showing off the things that matter most: my partner, Stella, and my cats, Storm, Lupin, Grey Thing, and Broomhilda.</string>
    <string name="projects_title">Things I made</string>
    <string name="work_title">Things I have worked on</string>
    <string name="school_title">Things they taught me</string>
    <string name="school_name">Louisiana State University</string>
    <string name="school_location">Baton Rouge, Louisiana, USA</string>
    <string name="school_degree">Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering</string>
    <string name="school_years">August 2009 - May 2013</string>
    <string name="school_description">When I was starting college, I was very close to going in to chemical engineering, because I loved chemistry. But the advisor told me being color blind could cause problems, so I took my interest in electronics and computers and went into electrical engineering instead. I spend my college years taking classes like circuits, microprocessors, optical electronics, control systems, and microfluidic biochips. I also took two semesters of C++, which made me promise to never be a software developer. It wasn’t until years later that I learned I didn’t hate programming, I just hated C++.\n\nOutside of class I worked the electrical engineering department’s help desk and spent some time as a network infrastructure technical for the university. I also was active in the LSU chapter of IEEE, eventually serving as President of the chapter during my senior year.</string>
</resources>