<resources>
    <string name="bio">I am an Android developer and Engineering Manager at Stø (BankID BankAxept). I have been making mobile apps for %1$s years, and have been an engineer for %2$s. I like my cats, tv shows, single player story-driven games, and avoiding conversations about hobbies so people don't think I am boring. I dislike billionaires, inequality, and hateful people. I also dislike people who appear in the Epstein files.\n\nWhen I am not writing code, I spend a lot of my time figuring out how to make the workday as smooth as possible. I am a huge proponent of effective communication, and hate the overly formal and rigid structures that a lot of companies try to use in the workplace.</string>
    <string name="footer">Written with Compose Multiplatform for %1$s!</string>
    <string name="personal_message">I can't have a personal website without showing off the things that matter most: my partner, Stella, and my cats, Storm, Lupin, Grey Thing, and Broomhilda.</string>
    <string name="personal_soapbox">Though this website is mostly a portfolio of things I have done, the state of the world compels me to also use it as a soapbox. Since I was a teenager I have had a very strong moral compass. I really value equality and kindness and empathy over anything. When I filled out my US Census form in college, I wrote in “human” as a race because I think that is where the world needs to be. We are all here sharing this planet together. Borders are imaginary, and the earth is such a small part of the universe as a whole.\n\nBut now more than ever we are being grouped and divided. It is like we haven’t learned anything at all and wars are still being waged over stories told by desert farmers thousands of years ago. And if it isn’t beliefs, it is ideologies, or skin color, or economic situations. Just anything to attack our neighbors; the ones we share a common history with. If you go back far enough in history, we all have a shared origin, so why are there so many arbitrary definitions of what makes us different from each other when, at the core, we are all the same?\n\nThe US is currently being run into the ground and divided by a group of hateful bigots led by a small, angry man. Respect is out the window, and he has been able to prey on the innate animal fear of something different from yourself, causing previously kind and caring people to turn into rude, racist, prejudiced, and entitled individuals. A cadre of pedophilic liars has created a cult to manipulate people into their own personal army of hate under the guise of politics. The utter dismantling of the trust of both the government and the foundations of science will not affect just America, because it is something that can spread like a disease if we let it.\n\nGetting into specifics would make this much too long, and I would have trouble keeping this updated since there are new atrocities every day. We need to use our voices to fight this. We need to use our voices to fight for our neighbors. We need to use our voices to fight for science, and for reason, and for kindness. We need to use our voices to unite! The enemy is not the person who lives across the street. The enemy is the idea that the person who lives across the street is your enemy. The enemy is the people who are spreading that idea. Those people — the ones who control 99% of the resources — are the ones we need to stand up against. There are so many more of us than there are of them, and if we could all speak together we could not be beaten.\n\nIf you read this, thank you, and please speak up somewhere. If you read this and you disagree, please do some real introspection to figure out why you feel this way, and realize that somebody else has told you to be angry. You do not have to be hateful, that is your own choice. Which side of history do you want to be on?</string>
    <string name="personal_title">Personal info</string>
    <string name="project_1_description">A collaborative effort between myself and tattoo artist Gunnar V, PICKY aims to help tattoo artists focus on their art by making all of the other stuff a lot easier.\n\nThe app handles things like client and ink management, helps pick which inks you should use to tattoo an image and helps mix inks to make other colors. It also has a handful of built-in algorithms to make stencils specifically for tattooing, letting you print these stencils directly from the app.\n\nPicky is a Compose Multiplatform app primarily made for iPads. Since it is targeted at tattoo artists, that is what the vast majority of the user base uses.</string>
    <string name="project_1_title">PICKY</string>
    <string name="project_2_description">I also have a Linux server I tinker with. This helps me make sure I'm only mostly super specialized in app development. It has the added benefit of me being able to understand up to half of what the backend and dev ops people are talking about in meetings!\n\nI use Mint because I'm afraid of headless (go ahead, judge me) and manage all of my services with Docker. I manage a bunch of things for my household like a personal media server, home automation, and a private cloud. It is also a fun testing ground for me to try out other things like self hosted LLMs.</string>
    <string name="project_2_title">Home server</string>
    <string name="projects_title">Things I've made</string>
    <string name="school_degree">Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering</string>
    <string name="school_description">When I was starting college, I was very close to going in to chemical engineering, because I loved chemistry. But the advisor told me being color blind could cause problems, so I took my interest in electronics and computers and went into electrical engineering instead. I spend my college years taking classes like circuits, microprocessors, optical electronics, control systems, and microfluidic biochips. I also took two semesters of C++, which made me promise to never be a software developer. It wasn’t until years later that I learned I didn’t hate programming, I just hated C++.\n\nOutside of class I worked the electrical engineering department’s help desk and spent some time as a network infrastructure technical for the university. I also was active in the LSU chapter of IEEE, eventually serving as President of the chapter during my senior year.</string>
    <string name="school_location">Baton Rouge, Louisiana, USA</string>
    <string name="school_name">Louisiana State University</string>
    <string name="school_title">Things they taught me</string>
    <string name="school_years">August 2009 - May 2013</string>
    <string name="see_on_github">Check it out on GitHub</string>
    <string name="website">Website</string>
    <string name="work_title">Things I've worked on</string>
    <string name="work_ai_description">AI Description:</string>
    <string name="work_my_part">My part:</string>
    <string name="work_1_description">Kongsberg Maritime is a global leader in providing cutting-edge technology and solutions for the maritime industry, with a strong focus on dynamic positioning (DP) systems. These sophisticated, computer-controlled systems automatically maintain a vessel's position and heading, using its own propulsion and thrusters to counteract environmental forces like wind, waves, and currents. Kongsberg's K-Pos series of DP systems are particularly renowned for their reliability and advanced functionality, enabling a wide range of vessels—from drill ships to cruise liners—to perform complex operations safely and efficiently in challenging conditions where anchoring or mooring is not feasible.</string>
    <string name="work_1_location">Saint Rose, Louisiana, USA and Kongsberg, Norway</string>
    <string name="work_1_tasks">I first worked for Kongsberg Maritime as an intern in 2012, the summer before my senior year of college. I mainly worked on dynamic positioning software. Once I became a full time employee after graduation, I was a System Engineer focusing on the software control systems of various vessels around the world. I would travel to these vessels to perform maintenance or upgrades. Eventually, I received specialized training in thruster control systems and moved to Norway to become a Project Engineer, configuring dynamic positioning and thruster control systems for new vessels. I would configure the systems from scratch, perform lab tests with clients and DNV (registrar and classification society) and eventually travel to commission the new vessel on a sea trial. This job taught me how to work in a very high stress environment with a high focus on quality of work, since performing poorly could have environmental consequences.</string>
    <string name="work_1_title">Kongsberg Maritime</string>
    <string name="work_1_years">June 2013 - July 2016</string>
    <string name="work_2_description">Holte offers a comprehensive suite of mobile and web-based software solutions designed to streamline operations for construction companies. The software simplifies complex processes by providing tools for project management, time and material tracking, and quality assurance directly from the construction site. Its mobile apps, such as HoltePortalen, enable project managers and workers to access project data, log work hours, and document progress with photos and attachments, ensuring real-time communication and up-to-date information across all project stakeholders.</string>
    <string name="work_2_location">Oslo, Norway</string>
    <string name="work_2_tasks">Holte was my first app development job, which was something I had only done as a hobby previously. At the time, the company used Xamarin Native, so I worked with native Android and iOS APIs in a C# wrapper. At the time I was there, we had a suite of 5 different apps and a dashboard app that connected them all together. We had libraries for shared logic like a network stack and storage, but the UI was all native. Since the company did not have mobile designers, that task fell to me through my own initiative.</string>
    <string name="work_2_title">Holte</string>
    <string name="work_2_years">August 2016 - July 2019</string>
    <string name="work_3_description">NRK, the Norwegian Broadcasting Corporation, is Norway's public service broadcaster, offering a wide range of content on its national television and radio channels. A core component of its service is NRK TV, a popular streaming platform that provides on-demand access to its extensive library of series, documentaries, news, and films. The service is known for its high-quality, inclusive programming and a user-friendly interface that makes it easy for viewers in Norway to stream content at no cost, reflecting NRK's mission to make media accessible to the entire population.</string>
    <string name="work_3_location">Oslo, Norway</string>
    <string name="work_3_tasks">At NRK, I mainly worked on the NRK TV streaming app for Android TV and Android devices. This was my first job working with Kotlin in a fully native Android environment. In addition to working on the Android team for NRK TV, I was also fagansvarlig (which loosely translates to technical lead) for the group of mobile app developers at NRK. Some of the things I am most proud of about the NRK TV app are our custom Android TV framework since we found Leanback to be too restrictive, and the Kotling Flow-based login library to be used across mobile apps. Since this app was a public service, there was also a strong focus on accessibility and universal design.</string>
    <string name="work_3_title">NRK</string>
    <string name="work_3_years">August 2019 - March 2021</string>
    <string name="work_4_description">Vipps is Norway's leading mobile payment platform, widely used by both individuals and businesses. Developed by a consortium of Norwegian banks, the app allows users to easily send and receive money using only a phone number, eliminating the need for bank account details. Beyond peer-to-peer transfers, Vipps has evolved into a comprehensive solution for online and in-store payments, paying bills, and even logging in to various websites and services. Its seamless integration into everyday Norwegian life has made it an essential tool for everything from splitting a restaurant bill with friends to paying for goods at a local store.</string>
    <string name="work_4_location">Oslo, Norway</string>
    <string name="work_4_tasks">I was a consultant during my tenure at Vipps during COVID, where the whole world had to learn how to work again. At Vipps, I was on the Vennebetaling team that focused on the peer to peer functionality in the Vipps app. During my time there, my vertical-slice team of product, backend, QA, Android, and iOS rewrote the entire groups and settlements features from the ground up. This is the functionality behind sharing and splitting payments with friends. Besides groups and settlements, one of my main focuses at Vipps was pushing the app into the Jetpack Compose era where we were using alpha and beta libraries before best-practices were really defined. I had a big focus on animations and making the app feel more “fun”.</string>
    <string name="work_4_title">Vipps</string>
    <string name="work_4_years">April 2021 - October 2022</string>
    <string name="work_5_description">BankID is the leading electronic identification and digital signature solution in Norway, used by over 4 million people daily to securely access a wide range of services. It is essential for everything from logging into your online bank and government websites to signing legally binding documents and authorizing payments. The mobile app has revolutionized its use, allowing users to verify their identity with biometrics like facial recognition and fingerprints, replacing the need for physical code devices. This seamless integration into daily life has even extended to physical identity verification, with the app offering a digital ID card feature that can be used at places like the post office and liquor stores to confirm a user's identity and age when picking up packages or purchasing age-restricted goods.</string>
    <string name="work_5_location">Oslo and Bergen, Norway</string>
    <string name="work_5_tasks">Besides being an Android developer, I am currently the engineering manager for all of the app developers at Stø, where we are 5 Android and 5 iOS developers. As a leader and a member of the App Foundation team, a lot of my time is spent coordinating things with the different product teams to keep a holistic view of the app from both a user's perspective and a developer's perspective. I have worked on all parts of the apps making core components like the network stack and the design system, and have rearchitected a lot of the app around Jetpack Compose and modern best practices. I have also suffered through dealing with the flaky Android keystore and other security related parts of the app, most importantly implementing our new DPoP (Demonstrating Proof-of-Possession) security architecture.</string>
    <string name="work_5_title">Stø (BankID)</string>
    <string name="work_5_years">November 2022 - Present</string>
</resources>